伦敦
1896年8月3日
霍雷肖・科森斯医生
三年后
早上好 特鲁夫人
Good morning, Mrs. True.
特鲁夫人
Mrs. True.
阿代尔小姐
Miss Adair.
-你太美了  -谁说不是呢
- You look very fine. - I think so, too.
圣罗毛尔达孤儿院
我是问 你在这转来转去干什么
What are you walking around here for? That's what I'm saying.
-我只是...  - 不是 等会儿
-Oh, I just... -No, wait!
您快管管这个人吧
Will you do something about this man, please?
快来看看"星辰报"
Read it in "The Star"!
玛拉黛手下的第五名受害者
Maladie kills fifth victim!
玛拉黛杀人
这场杀人狂欢让开膛手杰克都相形见绌
Murder spree soon to eclipse The Ripper!
你应该还感应不到结果吧
I don't suppose you know how this all works out.
这又不是随叫随到的
The ripplings don't come when they're called.
那我们还是尽量礼貌点
Well, let's just try to keep it civil.
别像对待旅店老板那样
Not like with the innkeeper.
-那是因为他有猎枪  -这借口我听过了
- He had a shotgun. - I've heard that excuse before.
谁叫他们都有猎枪
When they have shotguns.
-这女孩 什么情况  -桃金娘・哈普利琪
- What's the, uh, girl? - Myrtle Haplisch.
跟她的声音有关
Something to do with her voice.
日安 哈普利琪先生
Good day, Mr. Haplisch.
你们好
Yes.
-你是...  -我是阿玛莉亚・特鲁
-Are you, uh... -I'm Amalia True.
这位是我的同事 派南斯・阿代尔
This is my colleague, Penance Adair.
牧师告知你我们会前来拜访吗
The reverend told you we were coming?
是的 桃金娘的事
Oh, yeah. About Myrtle.
请... 进
Um, come... in.
太太
Missus!
请 到会客室来吧
Please, come through to the, um, parlor.
他们说 桃金娘可能... 被附魔了
They're saying Myrtle might be... Touched?
过去几年 我们听说过那些姑娘的事
We, we heard about those girls the last few years.
她们... 不太对劲
They're... not right.
对或是错 被附魔并不属于人格缺陷
Neither right nor wrong, being Touched is not a defect of character.
但那个杀人犯...
But isn't that killer...
玛拉黛 她不就是其中一员吗
Mal-Maladie. Isn't she one of them?
玛拉黛嗜杀成性 但我不知道她是否被附魔
Maladie's homicidal. I don't know if she's Touched.
-桃金娘也不能确定  -她肯定是附魔之人
- We don't know if Myrtle is. - Oh, she's Touched, all right.
被红靴子泰迪附魔的
Touched by Red Boot Teddy!
我们一致认为 存在一种邪恶的力量
We're, um, of a mind, there's a Satanic element.
她是路西法的容器
She's Lucifer's vessel, is what.
借她之口说话
He speaks through her.
上楼去
Up!
其实 牧师也提到她口齿不清
Yes, uh, the reverend mentioned an affliction of the tongue.
那是因为撒旦正盘踞在她身上
'Cause old Satan is squattin' on it.
吐出他的污言秽语
Spewing out his foulness,
把我们桃金娘的嘴搞得跟夜壶一样恶臭
making a chamber pot of our Myrtle's mouth.
那有点过于形象了
Well, that's a bit descriptive.
新买的水壶
new kettle.
-水开的话就...  -索菲
-It tells you when it's, um... -Sophie!
桃金娘现在在家吗
Is Myrtle here at home, then?
-为什么要用链子拴着她  -以防传染
- Why is she chained? - Infection.
家里还有其他人呢
W-w-we got the others.
出去 我说出去
Out. Get out. Get out, I say.
桃金娘是唯一一个新劳工法出台后能挣到钱的人
Myrtle was the only one could earn a wage with the new labor laws.
现在成这样了
Now this.
桃金娘 我是派南斯 这位是特鲁夫人
Myrtle, I'm Penance and that's Mrs. True.
我能坐下吗
May I sit?
我们是来帮你解决你的烦恼的
we've come to help with what's been troublin' ya.
有很多女孩跟你一样
There's plenty of girls who've been shown
出现了类似的异象 一种"转变"
a strangeness of some kind. A "turn."
但特鲁夫人和我帮助了她们 结果都很好
But Mrs. True and I, we've worked with them, and they come up fine.
想要我们帮助你吗
Would you like that?
说话啊 桃金娘
Speak, Myrtle.
应该是"说话啊 撒旦"
You mean, "Speak, Satan"?
你看吧
See?
桃金娘 你能听懂我说话吧
Myrtle, you can understand me, yes?
中文
Chinese?!
大部分吧 其中一些是俄语
Most of it. Some of it may have been Russian.
其他的应该是... 土耳其语
And I want to say... Turkish?
我的猜测是 她脑子里塞满了现有已知的语言
I'd guess every known language is crowding her mind.
桃金娘这样的女孩怎么会懂中文
How would a girl like Myrtle learn Chinese?
她甚至都没见过中国人
She's never even seen a Chinaman.
至少我们能排除
Well, at least we can rule out
邪恶力量这个选项了
any sort of Satanic influence.
-那些杂技演员  -什么
- Those acrobats. - What?
不是 他们只是滚来滚去罢了
No! They just tumbled about.
他们来巴尼公园表演空翻和平衡技巧
They come to Barney Park doing flips and balancing.
他们浑身散发着邪气
They had an unnatural air.
我之前就说过 还有一只猴子
I said it then. And there was a monkey!
-它直勾勾地盯着我  -是...
- He looked right at me. - Yes. Well...
-我就直说了...  -感谢你们给我们机会
- Allow me to be frank... - After being grateful
为桃金娘提供帮助...
for the chance to give Myrtle the kind of care...
别让他们上来
Keep them down here.
果然
Right.
先生们
Gentlemen.
你们能礼貌点吗
Might we be civil?
贱人
You bitch!
派南斯
Penance!
发光体
Shiner!
找辆马车来
Get the carriage!
爸爸 那位女士跟他们摔跤来着
Da! The lady did a wrestle!
快 我们走
Come on. Let's go!
就是现在 桃金娘 快跑
Now! Myrtle, run!
特鲁
True!
你看见那人的脸了吗
Did you see that face?
我觉得还是带枪的人好对付
I think I preferred when people just had shotguns.
不不不 我错了
Oh, no. No, I didn't.
我们跑不过他们 我们得变形
We can't outrun them. We're going to have to change it out.
你是说... 可这只是个原型机啊
you mean... It's only a prototype.
我们也觉得不可思议
This is weird for us, too.
低头
Heads down!
快让开
Out of the way!
让一让
One side!
我觉得你最好跟我们呆一块儿
I, I think it's best if you come stay with us for a bit.
如果你愿意的话
If that suits ya.
我们能 我们能一起对付他们
We can, we can deal with those fellas.
搞清楚他们的目的 或者他们是谁
We can find out what they want, or what they
我们要怎么对付他们
are. How are we gonna deal with those fellas?
特鲁
True?
去歌剧院
We're going to the opera.
看见没 我们已经有计划了
See? We already got a plan.
永不者
第一季 第 1 集
就一个女人
It's just a woman.
杀了五个男人 我敢说她的能力远不止如此
Five men murdered. I'd say she's more than that.
确实 谋杀
Yes, murder.
真够让人头疼的
Very distressing.
"玛拉黛"就是个疯子
This "Maladie" is a lunatic.
佩妮插图报 上帝的天使纷纷陨落
苏格兰场已经安排特勤人员去抓她了
Scotland Yard has their Special Detail to catch her.
无论她是否被附魔 都不值得我们管
What matter if she's Touched? This is beneath us.
精神分析师们 小心
她杀的不是妓女 阁下
She is not killing whores, your grace.
是受人尊敬的绅士
These are respectable men.
别仰望天堂 会让你盲目
上帝
精神分析学家罢了
Psychoanalysts.
首相打算
Well, the Prime Minister intends to take
对附魔之人公开表态
a public position on the Touched.
我们得决定立场问题
We need to decide what it is.
不过是几个女人耍耍把戏罢了...
A few women pulling parlor tricks...
不只是女人
It's not just women.
也不只是几个
And it's not a few.
至少得有上百人
There are hundreds, at least,
染上这种罕见又让人费解的怪病
of unique, inexplicable afflictions.
拉维妮娅・毕德罗为他们开展慈善事业
Lavinia Bidlow has made a cause of them.
这也是为何首相需要...
Which is why the PM needs to take a...
女士们受到了攻击
Women are being attacked,
被指控施加巫术或某种远域巫毒 并...
accused of witchcraft, or some island voodoo, and...
无稽之谈
Fairy stories.
这些不过是电流引起的
These are biological anomalies,
生理异常现象
caused by electricity.
马森勋爵 你怎么看
Uh, Lord Massen?
有个女孩上个月开始在我的发电机厂上班
A girl started in my engine works last month
负责擦拭压光机
wiping down the plating press.
她滑了一跤 手臂被压力机夹住了
She slipped. Got her arm caught in the press.
然后她没事人一样把手臂拽出来
And then she pulled it back out.
三吨重的压力啊
Three tons of pressure,
还弄断了液压轴承 却毫发无伤
and she snapped the hydraulic without so much as a bruise.
-人们欢呼  -不如招她入伍吧
- People cheered. - Well, I say enlist her.
派她去攻打该死的布尔人
Point her at the bloody Boers.
[布尔人 南非白人]
坏了台机器而已 我还是那句话 先生们
A machine breaks. Again, gentlemen,
这又不是军队部署
this isn't a troop deployment,
也不是市场崩盘
or a, a market crash.
首相是不会对"附魔之人"表态的
The Prime Minister will not be taking a position on the Touched.
也不会允许任何与此相关的官方讨论
Nor will he allow any official debate on the subject.
我们得先了解这次攻击的性质和规模
Not until we understand the nature and breadth of the attack.
-攻击  -你是说"附魔之人"
- Attack? - You're declaring the Touched
是对大英帝国的直接威胁吗
a direct threat against the empire.
我们誓死保卫的帝国
Which we here are sworn to protect.
万众一心 一致抗敌
Contra hostes omnes.
这场攻击预计将在何时...
And this attack is expected to come...
三年前就开始了
It came three years ago.
1896年8月3日
Third of August, 1896.
一个灰蒙蒙的周一
A Monday. Rather gray.
在那之前从未有人被"附魔"
Not one case of someone being Touched before then.
且都出现在伦敦
Not one outside London.
海外报道的那些附魔之人当时全在伦敦
Those reported overseas were all here at the time.
且位高权重的男性均未感染
And not one man of stature afflicted.
这才是厉害之处
That's the genius of it.
他们通过女性来攻击我们
They came at us through our women.
"他们"
"They"?
我还不确定几桩奇闻异事
I'm still not sure I can equate a few bizarre anecdotes
是否能称得上是大军攻击
with the Mongol horde.
只有庸君才需要让刀被刺进肚子
Only a blind man measures the length of a blade
去衡量刀长
by how much is in his belly.
-你说得太过了 马森  -这一切是设计好的
- Your overstep the mark, Massen. - This was designed
所以我们仅能管中窥豹
so that we would see the parts,
只见一斑
and not the whole.
像拉维妮娅・毕德罗那种慈善家
Philanthropists like Lavinia Bidlow
看到的是附魔之人的痛苦
see the suffering of the afflicted.
大众看到的则是一名冷血女杀手
The common throng see a macabre murderess.
而你看到的是台坏了的机器
And you see a broken machine.
这正是我所看到的
That is exactly what I see.
一台最伟大的机器
The greatest machine.
我们帝国之首府停滞不前
The heart of our empire brought to a shuddering halt
皆因那些人的反复无常和野心
by the caprice and ambitions of those
而曾经 野心于他们一无是处
for whom ambition was never meant.
这是力量至上的时代
This is the Age of Power.
-新的力量  -X光
- New power. - The X-ray.
-无线电  -电力
- The wireless. - Electricity.
我们是对革新习以为常的初代人
We are the first generation accustomed to the impossible.
女人们今天对此闻风丧胆
What women are appalled by today,
明天就会接受
they will accept tomorrow,
后天便也想要
and demand the day after that.
还有移民 和离经叛道之人
And the immigrant. And the deviant.
这种被操纵的力量 却不在我们掌控之中
That is the power being wielded, and not by us.
刀已落下 先生们
The blade is in, gentlemen.
我们要查出手握刀柄之人
We need to know whose hand is on the hilt.
.                      环线
前往火车站             .
别让任何人进来
Nobody gets through.
再加把劲儿 琼斯
Put your back into it, Jones,
-你个懒鬼...  -遵命 长官
- you lazy... - Yes, sir.
再跟不上进度 你们就全给我滚蛋
We get any further behind, I'll pluck the lot of ya!
当着长官的面 放尊重点
Not in front of the officer. Show some respect.
蒙迪探长
Detective Mundi.
你是特勤组的 对吧
You're the Special Detail, yeah?
-你得看看这个  -是吗
- You're gonna wanna see this. - Am I?
小心头
Mind your head.
一名矿工被她的尸体绊倒了
Was a digger stumbled on her.
差点亲上了
Near had a kiss, they did.
这里 看见这些刺伤了吗
Here. You see the stab wounds?
大伙儿举着火把进来
These mates brung the torches in.
在墙上发现了这个
They spotted this on the wall.
看看我的大作
我是死亡天师
才知道是她干的
That's how they knew it was one of hers.
是条讯息
It's a message.
不是玛拉黛干的
Not from Maladie.
你怎么能确定
But how can you be sure?
她起码不会拼错
She can spell.
那个矿工认出受害者了吗
Did he recognize the victim? The digger?
没有
No.
也没法辨认 老鼠都把她的脸啃烂了
Well, not much to recognize, the rats having had a go.
经常有流浪汉和醉汉在这里躲着
You get vagrants and drunks taking shelter down here all the time.
这女人两者都不是
This woman was neither.
这是通往哪儿的
Where does this lead?
这本来是南线的维修隧道
It was meant to be the maintenance tunnel
但被废弃了
for the southern line, but it got scrapped.
扩建地铁任务繁重
There's too much to do, expanding the underground.
这座城早晚得塌了
The city'll fall in on itself.
你这工作我可干不来
I don't envy you this job.
-是啊  -谁动了尸体
- Yeah. - Who moved the body?
一定是... 等等 什么
Must have been... Wait. What?
-没人 一直都在这  -她不是在这儿被杀的
- No, it was there. - She wasn't killed there.
她的血比墙上的猪血干得早多了
And her blood's been dry a lot longer than this pig's.
不 不是...
No. It's not... Oi.
你怎么乱加揣测啊
You're tossing about a lot of assumptions.
显然 这是我的职责
Clearly I meant to.
好了 全面停工 排成一排
Right. Shut this lot down. Line 'em up.
-不...  -我们得检查这里的每个人
- No... - We check every man in here
看看谁手上或者衣服上有血迹
for blood on his hands or his clothes.
你 你不能叫我们停工 我们有进度要赶
You, you can't stop the dig. We got a schedule to keep.
谋杀还比不上赶进度呢 是吧
And what's a murder to that, eh?
怎么 你以为自己是第一个试图嫁祸给玛拉黛的人吗
What? You think you're the first to try and pin something on Maladie?
人们一遇上附魔之人都以为是她
People think every Touched they meet might be her.
他们之中某些人 确实够奇怪的
And some of them Touched, they're weird enough. They are.
让人起鸡皮疙瘩 而你
Make your skin crawl. But here's you,
放任真凶逍遥法外
letting a killer get off by making it harder to catch another one.
-就为了赶工作进度  -你这人我知道 弗兰克・蒙迪
- For a schedule. - I know about you, Frank Mundi.
东城猿人 总爱以拳头制人
East End Ape. Always fists first.
死人都能被你揪上来逼供认罪
He could beat a confession out of a headstone.
你尽管装成正义的化身
You can play the righteous man,
但就算是你 也是替人办事
but even you answer to someone.
没错 就替她
Yes, I do. She's right there.
现在 那个女人惨死
Now, that woman faced an horrible end.
我不认为你是凶手
And I don't think you killed her,
但也不会让你埋葬她
but I'm not letting you bury her.
你不是特勤组的吗
What about the Special Detail?
凶手如果不是玛拉黛 那这案子就不归你管
If it's not Maladie done this, then it's not your case.
不 就是玛拉黛干的
Oh, no. Maladie done this, didn't she?
因为她在墙上留了言
Because she left a message.
所以你给我从实招来 你动手脚之前墙上写的什么
So you're gonna tell me what was here before you dressed it up,
再说谎试试 我可不光是在破案
'cause one more lie, and I'm not on a case,
我他妈可是"死亡天师"
I'm the fucking "Angle" of Death.
别关门
Leave the doors!
特鲁夫人带了个新人回来
Mrs. True's back with a new one.
她们开着派南斯的... 原型机
They's in Penance's... Uh, the prolatype.
什么 那辆自动马车吗
What, the auto-carriage?
太神奇了 普丽姆罗丝 快来看看
It's mad. Primrose, you got to see.
妈妈说了机动车很常见
Mother says motorcars are common.
普通吗 一共就八辆啊
Common? There's only eight of them that ever were.
我不指望你会明白
I wouldn't expect you to understand,
但妈妈说它们是个祸害
but Mother says they're a blight.
是吗 她最近说的吗
Yeah? She say that lately?
可能是她某次来访 我们都不在吧
On a visit, maybe, that we all missed.
-说得好像你知道怎么当母亲一样  -普丽姆罗丝
- As though you know anything about being a mother. - Primrose!
-她不是这个意思  -她是觉得长大了就不会被打屁股吗
- She didn't mean that. - Does she think she's too big for a spanking?
我们来啦
Coming through!
好了好了 来吧
All right. All right, come on.
别围着了 只是辆马车而已
Don't suffocate them. It's only a carriage.
居然不是
No?
这太他妈帅了
That's fuckin' amazing.
桃金娘 这是霍雷肖・科森斯医生 他经常骂骂咧咧的
Myrtle, this is Dr. Horatio Cousens. He swears a lot.
我才没有
No, I don't.
-旅途如何  -挺精彩的
- How was your journey? - Eventful.
露西 我要写封信给毕德罗夫人
Lucy, I need to send a letter to Mrs. Bidlow.
告诉她我们被袭击的事
Let her know about the attack.
袭击 发生了什么
Attack? What attack?
露西 把笔和纸准备好
Lucy. Pen. Paper.
我在你房间准备一下
I'll set up in your rooms.
-先谈公事  -不行
- Shop talk first. - Not first.
只是擦伤而已
This is just a scratch.
-普丽姆罗丝  -我坐不进去
- Primrose? - I can't ride it in,
-我看不出…  -不是…
-so I don't see what... -No, it's just...
我记得你说没有同龄人说说话
I recalled you saying you didn't have anyone your own age to talk to.
我是查塔韦小姐
I'm Miss Chattoway.
叫我普丽姆罗丝就好
But you may call me Primrose.
希望我们能成为朋友
I hope we'll be friends.
所以你的"转变"是什么 我是变大了
So what's your "turn"? I'm large.
桃金娘语言上异于常人
Myrtle has a language situation,
我想她可以先喝杯茶
and I imagine she could use a cup of tea.
-好的 你想…  -她懂英语
- Oh. Um, do you want... - She does speak English.
只是说不出来而已
But not with her mouth.
好的 和我来吧
All right. Come with me.
我们应该在这车里结婚
We should be married in this.
这有什么新鲜的
How is this new?
自打知道我们被附魔以后 人们就开始攻击我们
People been attacking us since they known we was Touched.
-或者说一直都是  -这次不一样
- Or since always. - This is different.
这一整天
This whole day.
我们越是蓬勃发展 他们就越会抨击我们
We knew people would come down on us the more we were thriving.
-他们为什么会想要…  -桃金娘吗
- Why would they want this... - Myrtle?
我猜她不是第一个
I don't think she's the first.
我觉得他们这样做已经有一段时间了
I think they've been doing this for some time.
有些女孩我们一到 她们就恰巧"跑掉了"
All those girls we went after who'd "just run away"?
老天
Lord.
我们要加固防备
We need to bolster our security.
所有出口 门窗都要守好或锁死
All entrances, windows bolted or blocked.
我可以给他们准备些小惊喜
I could rig up a few surprises, as well.
不会造成致命伤害 但能劝退他们
Nothing lethal, but very discouraging.
每个人进出都要登记时间和目的地
Everyone signs in and out. Time and destination.
不能独自外出 天黑也不许出门
No one goes out alone or after dark.
-不允许访客进入  -就那一次
- Not even visitors. - One time.
我一直在教女孩们格斗技巧
I've been showing the girls a bit of scrapping.
-你倾囊相授  -但别用她们的"转变"
- You'll show them all. - But not using their "turns."
手头有的这些就足够了
Well, there's plenty you can do with what's at hand.
自信最重要 就像我妈妈之前说的
It's about confidence. As my mum used to say,
如果你能直视一个男人的眼睛
if you can look a man in the eye,
你就能捅他眼珠子
you can stab him in it.
聪明的女人
Smart woman.
但别真这么做
But also, don't do that.
告诉乞丐王 我想见他
The Beggar King. Tell him I need to see him.
我们付钱让他保护我们
We pay him for protection,
他告诉我们疑似的附魔之人
and he's been feeding us potential candidates.
我们得知道他是不是把消息外泄了
I need to know if he's been feeding anyone else.
明天第一件事 在街上把话传开
Here, first thing tomorrow. Put word on the street.
这不太合规矩 特鲁夫人
That's not how it works, Mrs. True.
阿玛莉亚 乞丐王不会接受呼来喝去
Amalia, you don't just ask the Beggar King to come calling.
这也由不得他
I am, in fact, not asking.
好吧
All right.
我来给你看看伤口
Better tend to that scratch,
既然你忙着给自己树敌
since you're in such a hurry to make new enemies.
奥古斯都・毕德罗想见您 先生
Augustus Bidlow to see you, sir.
奥吉 抱歉让你久等了
Augie, sorry I kept you waiting.
你等很久了吗 我对时间不太敏感
Did I keep you waiting? I'm at odds with time.
它们不开心了
They're unhappy.
谁 汉弗莱斯一家吗 当然了 他们太老了
Who? The Humphries? Of course they're unhappy. They're old.
那些乌鸦
The crows.
-它们不该在此聚集  -乌鸦啊…
- They shouldn't be massing here. - Crows...
你是说我们在目击一群乌鸦吗
Do you mean to say we're witnessing a murder?
["murder"是一群乌鸦的集合名词]
你知道我讨厌这个词
You know I hate that term.
太不公平了 用谋杀形容"一群乌鸦"
So unfair, "a murder of crows."
乌鸦很可爱 它们是有灵性的动物
Crows are actually lovely. They're intelligent creatures.
为什么形容一群云雀用"欣喜"
Why is it an "exaltation of larks"?
["exaltation"是云雀的集合名词]
-云雀根本不是…  -不是社会性动物
- Larks are not at all as soc... - Not at all as social.
奥吉 你对鸟类术语的激进立场
Yes, Augie, your radical stance on avian nomenclature
-从你上伊顿公学时就没变过了  -谢谢 不用了
- hasn't changed since Eton. - No, thank you.
我认为它们正是在这附和你的不满
I think they're here as a Greek chorus to your distemper.
所以…你怎么就炸毛了
So... what has you so ruffled?
我猜你姐姐又生气了
I assume your sister is angry about something.
没有啊
No.
只是…我做了件蠢事
I just... I, I've done something stupid.
但这不是她…
And that's not why she's... Fu...
她…这个
She... This.
你知道拉维妮娅的慈善机构在忙啥吗
You know Lavinia's charity endeavor?
附魔之人
The Touched.
是的 那些…
Yes. The, uh...
-孤儿院  -对 是孤儿
- The Orphanage. - Orphans. Right.
-不啊 附魔之人  -是的 他们太可怕了
- No. The Touched. - Yes. They're terrible.
他们很棒
They're wonderful.
很 荒唐可笑
They're absurd.
你知道这个词是什么意思吗
Do you even know what the term means?
"附魔"吗 当然 不知道
"Touched"? Yes! No.
她们都是… 都有…
Uh, they're all, uh, they have,
奇奇怪怪的畸形和缺陷
uh, weird, um, deformities and afflictions.
对了…奥尔德顿・斯格罗夫有个会悬浮的侄女
And... Oh! Um. Alderton Musgrove has a niece who can float.
-真的吗  -是的
- Really? - Yeah.
离地三厘米左右吧
Just an inch or so off the ground.
除非你拖她 不然她哪也去不了
She can't go anywhere unless you tow her about.
斯格罗夫气坏了
Musgrove is apoplectic.
我都不该说出来的
I'm not supposed to tell.
拉维妮娅给她们找了个家
Oh, and, uh, Lavinia's opened a, a home for them.
-争议还挺大的...  -然后
- And it's all rather controversial, and... - And
她刚从管事的寡妇那儿
she, she, she just now got word
听到了一些谣传
from the widow who runs the affair.
一些被附魔的姑娘遭到了袭击
Some Touched girl was attacked.
女孩没事 但拉维妮娅气坏了
I mean, the girl's fine, but Lavinia, she's aflame.
"是时候让社会接受
"It's time society accepted
附魔之人就在你我之间 他们…"
that the Touched are amongst us, and they're... ".
但我说 "她们并不在我们之中
And I said, "Well, they're not amongst us.
她们在孤儿院呢"
You know, they're in The Orphanage."
然后她说我真是个天才
And she called me a genius.
这比她叫我蠢货还膈应 因为…
Which is worse than when she calls me an idiot, because...
我猜不透她…
I, I never know what she...
她要带她们去歌剧院
She's bringing them to the opera.
就今晚 坐我们的包厢
Tonight! In our box.
为了这些女人她把范・阿尔德斯夫妇都赶出去了
She's ousted the Van Alders for these wo-women.
让我去凑成四个人
I'm to make the fourth.
-她们长得很丑吗  -我不知道
- Are they hideous? - I've no idea.
就…
It's, um...
是那个寡妇 特鲁女士
It's, it's, it's the widow, Mrs. True,
应该吧 还有她的同伴
I think, and her companion.
你觉得她们会长得很丑吗
Do you think they might be hideous?
不管怎么样 和那个丑的调情
Well, whatever they are, flirt with the ugly one.
这会造就一种意想不到的和谐
It creates an unexpected balance.
我不知道要怎么调情
I don't know how to flirt.
老天啊 这些人让我觉得好不安
God, these people make me uneasy.
如果是那种扭曲畸形的女的呢
What if she's some sort of Elephant Man woman?
嗯 那她就是丑的那个了
Well, then, she's probably the ugly one.
你一定要来
You have to come.
去歌剧院吗
Oh! To the opera?
是啊 调情你最会了
Well, you know everything about flirting.
而且 你也不介意奇奇怪怪的人
Plus, you don't mind when people are odd.
所以我们才成了朋友
It's how we're friends.
但今晚演得是"浮士德"啊
But it's "Faust"!
拜托了
Please?
让我做什么都行 我是说...
I'll do anything. I mean...
就拉维尼亚对于这个团体的热情
People are already saying unkind things
已经有人开始嚼舌根了
about Lavinia's passion on the subject.
如果这事出个什么差错...
If this whole thing doesn't go smoothly...
我跟财政大臣还有个重要会议
I've got a very important meeting with the Minister of Finance
关于摆渡者的下一次午夜狂欢
about The Ferryman's next Midnight Carouse.
摆渡者 我不...
The Ferryman's? I don't...
等一下 财政大臣跟你的异教徒性爱俱乐部
Sorry, wh-what does the Minister of Finance have to do
有什么关系
with your pagan sex club?
他得做点什么
Whatever he has to do
才能从我手里拿到上次我拍的照片
to get the pictures I have from the last one.
俱乐部就是这么运作的
That's how the club works.
这挺微妙的
It's all quite delicate.
利益 威胁 然后
Favors and threats, and then,
一个逍遥法外的美好夜晚
one shining night where no law yet exists.
它不只是俱乐部 这是种社会思潮
It's more than just a club. It's an ethos.
我不会跟一群我认识且厌恶的人一起
And I won't sit through three hours of moralistic bellowing
忍受三个小时的道德洗礼
with everyone I know and hate,
就因为拉维妮娅变得神经兮兮
just because Lavinia's gone weird.
她没有神经兮兮
She's not weird.
是我粗俗了
I'm an ape.
-但她确实对你呼来喝去  -我知道
- But she does push you around. - I know.
我懂
I know.
我今晚会去的
I will come tonight.
-只要...  -不是 我吗
- If... - No. Me?
参加摆渡者 不行 雨果 求你了 我...
At The Ferryman's? No. Hugo, no. Please. I...
性爱俱乐部是...
Sex club is just...
就是更可怕级别的调情
That's just flirting on a much scarier level.
你不需要去调情
You don't have to flirt.
你只要放松
You just have to relax.
然后忍受别人来撩你就行
Endure someone flirting with you.
这是我的条件
These are my terms.
真是个呆子
Oh, he's a pokey one.
对这个社会而言
As far as society is concerned,
奥古斯都・毕德罗无可指摘
Augustus Bidlow is above reproach,
也让人不屑一顾
and beneath contempt.
-他很完美  -对什么来说
- He's perfect. - For what?
你不用再扮女仆了
You don't have to wear that anymore.
啊对 你就是女仆
Oh. Right. You are the maid.
我喜欢看你工作
I like watching you work.
好像你在指挥一样
It's like you're conducting.
乞丐王那儿再出点岔子
Well, get in wrong with the Beggar King,
你就能听上交响曲了
and you'll get a symphony.
你这真是大材小用
You shouldn't be in that life.
你这天赋 你应该成为皇家御医
Gift like yours, you should be the Royal physician,
而不是给黑帮和怪胎们包扎
not patching up gangsters and freaks.
我这天赋给了我个巫医的招牌
Gift like mine gets me branded a voodoo witch doctor.
我也不挑三拣四了
I gave up being choosy.
都不说一句我不是怪胎吗
Nothing about me not being a freak?
别 进来吧 做个手术而已
Oh, no, just come in. It's only surgery.
这下好了
Oh, right.
我天晚上要去歌剧院
I'm going to the opera tonight.
我预见过这场景
I had a rippling.
"同我与我弟弟奥古斯都
"to accompany me and my brother Augustus
前往'浮士德'的开幕演出
to the opening performance of 'Faust.'
拉维妮娅・毕德罗"
Lavinia Bidlow."
所以你刚说你被人攻击了
So you send word that you'd just been attacked,
她就说"出来玩啊"
and she says, "Come out to play."
她连礼服都送来了
She even sent an outfit.
你不是还要养伤口呢吗
And what about the part where you rest?
我是去剧院 不是去干苦力
It's the theater, not hard labor.
而且 我... 觉得我需要到场
And I... Think I need to be there.
有麻烦吗
Trouble?
凯瑟琳马上准备好晚饭了
Katherine will have supper ready soon.
拉维妮娅觉得我穿得进这个
Does Lavinia really think I can fit into this?
这裙子很适合你
It's a good dress for you.
能帮忙压住伤口
It'll keep pressure on the wound.
-特鲁夫人  -阿代尔小姐
- Mrs. True. - Miss Adair.
你看起来真美
You look very fine.
我也这么觉得
I think so, too.
就像是故事书里的角色
It's like something from a storybook.
我觉得行屈膝礼有点困难
I'm not confident in my curtsying.
我觉得呼吸有点困难
I'm not confident in my breathing.
我都没打算喘气
Oh, I wasn't planning to breathe.
我觉得这会不太得体
I think it's considered rude.
-疼吗  -有点痒
- Does it hurt? - Itches.
那更糟糕
Aah, that's much worse.
你确定我们一定要去吗
Are you sure we need to go to this?
务必说是 不然我现在就哭 但...
You have to say yes or I'll cry, but...
我们必须要去
We need to go to this.
真想知道原因
Wish I knew why.
我们单独聊聊
Give us the room.
那是奥迪恩 原谅那臭味
That's Odium. Pardon the stench.
他根本就不愿意去洗澡
You cannot get that man into a bath.
德克兰・奥林
Declan Orrun.
乞丐王
The Beggar King.
或者...不是
Or, no...
-奥林先生 派南斯・阿代尔  -嗯 我认识
- Mr. Orrun, Penance Adair. - Yeah, I know.
-伟大的女发明家  -我没那么厉害
- The great inventress. - Oh, I'm not great.
-我猜你听说了...  -你知道现在是什么情况了吗
-I assume you've heard about... -Do you know how it looks?
街上人尽皆知 你对我呼来喝去
Every rum on the street hearing you calling me
就跟喊条母狗一样
come like a bitch puppy?
-我们有沟通渠道的  -我们今天遇袭了
- There's channels. - We were attacked today.
就一回
Only once?
他们跟我们同一时间去找了桃金娘・哈普利琪
They came for Myrtle Haplisch same time we did.
可能追踪改造人已有一段时间
Probably been after the Touched for some time,
但现在被我们发现了
but now they've been seen.
这对我们来说是个威胁 我不得不怀疑
They're a danger to us, and I'd suspect,
任何和我们有联系的人
anyone known to be connected with us.
所以你就把我们的关系搞得人尽皆知
Which you made sure I was known far and wide to be.
你唤我出来 让我只能帮你
You called me out, so I'd be forced to help you.
现在你还当面说了出来
And now you've told me that to my face.
我真的绞尽脑汁在想这事要怎么发展
I'm genuinely searching for a way that this spins out
我才不用杀了你
that I don't kill you.
你不杀我的结局会更好
It would be better if you didn't.
你这娘们可少见
You're a rare fuckin' bird.
你把桃金娘的消息卖给我们
You sold us the information about Myrtle.
然后你在想我是不是还卖给了其他人
And you're wondering if I sold it to someone else.
那你想去吧 小公主
Well, wonder away, princess.
那是我的生意
My business is mine.
除了我那神圣和谐的婚姻
Apart from the sanctity of my harmonious marriage,
专一什么的就是扯淡
fuck-all is exclusive.
我的姑娘们需要保护 而我需要消息
My girls need protection, and I need information.
我要独家情报 谁在追踪附魔之人以及原因
Exclusive, about who's hunting the Touched, and why.
别装模作样了 你开个价吧
Skip the posture and name your price.
你付不起这个价
You ain't got that kind of swag.
我们财源丰厚
We're resourceful.
是吗 你们能给我弄个王冠宝石吗
Is that so? How 'bout you get me the Crown fucking Jewels?
等等 不会来真的吧
Wait, are you considering that?
我们会先送你一份礼物 为今天的鲁莽赔罪
We'll start with a gift for today's thoughtlessness.
一辆自动马车 专为您设计
An automated motor-carriage, designed to your specifications.
你若帮忙 还会有酬劳
And you will be paid, if you help us.
你足够疯狂 值得一试
You're mad enough to make this worth it.
但因此你也有可能搞砸
But you're mad enough to try not to.
如果那样 我就把你的脸划烂
If it goes that way, I will cut your face to a mess.
这不是我的脸
This isn't my face.
我还以为你能吓唬到她们
I thought you was gonna scare them.
把手指伸开
Spread out your fingers.
-等等  -把手举起来
- Wait. - Hold up your hand,
他妈把手指给我张开了
and spread out your fuckin' fingers.
雨果 下来
Hugo, get off!
我要上台了
I have to go!
我第五幕洞穴芭蕾舞后就结束了
I'm done after the cavern ballet in act five,
就监狱那幕之前
right before the prison scene.
雨果 你在听吗
Hugo? You listening?
当然 监狱那幕
Yes. The prison scene.
没错
Yes.
你觉得呢 毕德罗小姐
Don't you agree, Miss Bidlow?
你非得跟我咬文嚼字吗
Must we fight a war over words?
我真是受够了那些危言耸听
I'm exhausted by these overwrought alarums
说我们的语言要被法语化了
about the Frenchification of our language.
这都到世纪末了
It's the end of the century.
这种根深蒂固的偏见一无是处
These ancient prejudices have no use.
贝尔登医生
Dr. Beldon,
想必涉及到你的精神分析实践
you adopt new terms as they become relevant
你经常会用到新的词汇
to your practice of psychoanalysis, I imagine.
近来每周如此
Practically every week of late.
语言所求的不是停滞 而是准确
Language requires not stasis, but specificity.
若能删掉”挺好“一词 我就太开心了
I should be thrilled to excise the word "nice."
这词像浆糊一样含混 对吧 奥古斯都
It's vague as paste. Isn't that right, Augustus?
奥古斯都
Augustus.
-抱歉  -我们之前还在说呢
- Sorry? - We were discussing it earlier.
现代语言的准确性
The specificity of modern language.
对对对 没错
Oh, yes. Yes, yes, yes.
挺好
It's very nice.
如果你们讨论的是法语词
If it's, uh, French terminology we're discussing,
那我想说 有些法语词
there are a few terms
在英语中 没有对应词
we Britons simply don't have a word for.
失陪一下
Oh, excuse me.
我想大家都知道他指的什么词
I suppose we all know the sort of terms he means.
斯旺来这里干什么
What on Earth is Swann doing here?
我... 不 我知道
I... No, I know.
太冲动了...
S-so impulsive...
马森勋爵 一切可好
Lord Massen. You're well, I hope.
毕德罗小姐 我很好 谢谢 贝尔登医生 斯旺 你好
I am, Miss Bidlow. Thank you. Dr. Beldon, hello. Swann.
我们正在讨论几个老家伙
We were discussing the panic a few old men are having
对法语词的恐惧心理
about certain French terms.
国会上也争论过类似话题 是缘起哪个词呢
There was one debated on the Parliament floor. What was it?
"雇员"
"Employees."
雇员 用这词不也没事吗
Employees. And here we say it, and yet live.
这是厌恶 而不是恐慌
It is not panicking to abhor something.
用外来的花言巧语
Neither is it useful to replace
[盎格鲁撒克逊语]
去代替完美的古英语
a perfectly good Anglo-Saxon word
并没有什么帮助
with some foreigner's flourish.
在英国 我们说"受雇者"
In England, we say "the employed."
替换成"雇员"有什么好处呢
What possible benefit in replacing it with "employees"?
单数形式
The singular.
我们可以指代一名雇员
One may refer to a single employee,
但是"受雇者"
whereas "the employed"
只能表示一个群体
can only be used to describe a mass of people.
它否定了单个劳动者
It doesn't allow for the idea that a single worker
也可以是完整而有意义的存在
may be a whole and meaningful being.
这是阿玛莉亚・特鲁夫人 阿代尔小姐
Mrs. Amalia True. Miss Adair.
我介绍一下 这是马森勋爵
May I introduce Lord Massen?
-特鲁夫人在打理孤儿院  -的确
- Mrs. True runs The Orphanage. - Indeed.
哪一个是长得丑的
Which one's the ugly one?
我想 你们也是
I take it then that you are yourselves
其中染病的一员吧
among the afflicted?
附魔之人 是的 但我们未受其扰
Touched, yes. We don't consider ourselves afflicted.
或许就病症而言 有些女性
Perhaps some women are more fortunate
比其他的更幸运一些
in the nature of their ailment than others.
话是没错 但
That's true, but,
她们遭受的痛苦更多来自社会偏见
more suffer from society's perception
而非自身的不适
than their own debilitation.
你们都有些什么毛病
Well, so what's wrong with you?
他是在说我呢
I, I think he means me.
-怎么说呢...  -不 你们看上去...
- Uh, where to begin... - No, it's just, you, you lo... you, you look...
挺好的
You're qu... You're quite nice.
你还在打理孤儿院
And you, um, y-you have the charity, The Orphanage.
看上去... 很正常
That seems... normal.
是毕德罗小姐经营孤儿院
Miss Bidlow runs The Orphanage.
我们只是受雇者
We're just the employed.
很令人震惊 但我弟弟说出了所有人的疑问
Shockingly, I'd say my brother has spoken for everyone.
他们急切想知道你们的"转变"是什么
They're anxious to know what your "turns" are.
-”转变“就是耍把戏  -不是把戏
- A "turn" is a trick. - It's not a trick.
派南斯擅长发明 是创造者
Penance is an inventor. A creator, really.
世上只有一个造物主
Oh. There's only one Creator.
我看得见能量
No, uh, I can see energy.
势能 就像电能
Potential energy. Like with electricity.
我能看到能量想往哪儿走
I can see where it wants to go, or,
是移动还是停滞
move, or settle.
这能帮助我组建一些东西
It helps me put things together.
你呢
And yours?
特鲁太太往往能走在我们前头
Mrs. True tends to be a few steps ahead of the rest of us.
预言家
A prognosticator.
没那么了不起
Nothing so grand.
所以我没法了解我的死因
So I shouldn't ask how I'm going to die.
不 但肯定会涉及到某个法语词
No, but one can safely assume it will involve a French word.
-你能看到未来  -片段而已
- You see the future? - Snippets.
有所帮助 但也会带来困惑
It's as confusing as it is useful.
你曾是一名军人
You were a soldier.
必然见过有人突然感觉自己回到了战场
You've seen men who suddenly feel themselves back in battle.
对我来说 就像是去到了未来
Well, sometimes I go forward.
我没说我是军人
I never said I was a soldier.
-也许你马上会说  -不 是你的眼睛
- You're probably going to. - No, it's the eyes.
一直在评估周边的威胁
Assessing every threat.
马森勋爵是抵御现代化侵害的...
Lord Massen is the last line of defense
最后一道防线
against the scourge of modernity.
我老了 见证了太多改变
I'm old and I've seen too much change
并不足以时代洪流 可是
to fight against the tide, but, uh,
混乱不是变化
chaos is not change.
群体靠大声疾呼来寻求认可并不代表他们值得
Shouting for recognition does not make a people worthy of it.
世界的和谐才是我们最该守护的
There's a harmony to our world that's worth preserving.
我认为
As I understand it,
和谐是由不同声音
a harmony is made up of different voices
发出的不同音符构成的
sounding different notes.
没错 但主音只有一个
Yes. And one is always above the other.
女士们 失陪
Ladies.
我杀死了恶魔
I killed the devil.
是玛拉黛
It's Maladie!
玛拉黛在此
It is Maladie!
她想干什么
What does she want?
没人说声"谢谢"吗
Is no one going to say "thank you"?
没事 没事
It's okay. It's okay.
没事的
It's okay.
没事的 花瓣 不是你的错
It's okay, petal. It's not your fault.
是医生的错
It's the doctor.
人可真多啊
Oh! Oh, there's so many people.
你们来的时候都戴帽子了吗
Did you all come in hats?
现在你们头上空空荡荡 对吗
Now all of your brains are naked. No?
你们就该戴着鳗鱼花冠
You shall have a wreath of eels
鱼尾伸进你们的嘴里
with the tail in your mouth.
求求你
Please!
Please.
别...走
Don't... go.
恶魔的特产就是鳗鱼
Devil's speciality is eels.
就是你们认为的毒蛇
Which is known by you as a serpent.
但只是亚当
Oh, but it's only Adam.
它们滑行起来时都一样
It's all the same when it slithers.
夏娃长着逼
Eve had a cunt.
我为什么在这里
Why am I here?
我是来杀一个天使女巫
I came to kill an angel witch.
不好意思
Oops.
可我离得越近 我越觉得
But the closer I came, the more I felt
我来这里...
I was here for a r...
因为我... 看见了上帝
Because I... saw God.
k散发着光芒
He was all light.
k为我带上了花冠 他来过
And He put on me His wreath. He came.
他来过所有人身边
He came to us all,
你们却对k不理不睬
and you all turned your backs on Him.
你们撒谎 你们说k从未来过
You lied. You said He never.
但k会低哼
But He makes hum.
k会歌唱
Oh, He sings.
我唱不出那样的声音
I could never make it out,
可我能感受到k的低哼
but I feel His hum,
就像喉咙中有把梳子
like a comb in my throat.
我能感受到
And I feel it.
我感受到了
I feel it.
k 就在这里
Him. Here.
是谁... 是谁...
Who... Who...
管他妈的 把天使杀了
Ah, bugger it. Take the angel.
什么都没有吗
Oh, nothing?
有人吗 告诉我你想要什么
Anyone? Tell me what you want!
我来这儿要么有原因 要么就是要烧了它
Either I am here for a reason, or for a bonfire.
不 她摔下去了
Oh, no! She fell!
有老鼠 小老鼠
Mice. Tiny mice.
你的鸡巴怎么还硬着
How is that still hard?
-快走  -他妈的
- Go. - Damn it.
快 别停
Come on, don't stop.
把她给我
Just let me have the girl.
把她给我...
Just let me have the girl...
不
No.
看你闯的祸 小夜莺
Well, you've made a mess, little songbird.
老大...
Boss...
雨果・斯旺
Hugo Swann.
斯旺勋爵
Lord Swann.
我就不计较你这次失礼了
But I'll overlook the breach this once.
我相信你这段时间过得很不容易
I'm sure this must be a very difficult time for you.
完全相反
On the contrary.
伦敦那个杀人如麻的疯子离我就像基蒂这么近
London's deadliest maniac was as close to me as Kitty is now.
-是凯蒂  -突然降临的死亡
- It's Katie. - And the presence of sudden death
让人更珍惜活着的时候
makes one appreciate the act of living.
他看起来是挺珍惜的
He did seem to appreciate it.
我要单独和勋爵谈谈 凯蒂
I'll need to interview his lordship alone, Katie.
-我不明白...  -这样能快一点
- I don't see why... -It'll be quicker.
但请不要离开剧院
But don't leave the theater, please.
我永远不会离开剧院的...
Oh, I could never leave the theater...
我想你根本没有尝试
So I don't suppose you made any effort
阻止玛拉黛
to stop Maladie.
我以为那是... 你的工作
I have it that that's... your job.
是那个小寡妇替你做的
Oh, and that there's a young widow doing it for you.
阿玛莉亚・特鲁
Amalia True.
拉维妮娅・毕德罗的客人 管理孤儿院
Guest of Lavinia Bidlow. Runs The Orphanage.
玛拉黛绑架了一个姑娘 特鲁夫人一直在追
Maladie kidnapped a girl. Mrs. True gave chase.
不幸之人的捍卫者
Champion of the unfortunate,
她还打倒了那个危险的男人
and she knocks dangerous men about.
你很幸运她不知道你们的算盘
Then I guess you're lucky she don't know what you're up to.
是我们
What we're up to.
我可把你当做伙伴
I think of you as a partner, in a way.
我没从这事里牟利
I don't profit by what we do.
我也没有
Well, neither do I.
还没有
Yet.
只要你送来足够多的漂亮姑娘
Once you've sent enough suitable girls my way,
有投资人的投资
and a certain investor is invested,
那摆渡者俱乐部
The Ferryman's Club will become
将不只是个盈利生意 还能有现象级的影响
not just a profitable business, but a phenomenon.
我甚至对一些债务视而不见
I might even forget a few debts.
快他妈把香槟喝了 弗兰克
Take the fucking champagne, Frank.
你会想要的
You'll want it.
我知道玛拉黛带走的女孩的名字
You see, I know the name of the girl Maladie took.
你也知道
And so do you.
通晓各种语言
One little polyglot.
一个被附魔的小女孩
One tiny Touched girl.
把她给我带来就行
That's all you had to bring me.
我喜欢这个词 "被附魔"
I like that word. "Touched."
就像上帝之手轻轻点了某些人
Like the finger of God gave a few of us a little poke.
将我们唤醒
Woke us up.
每个实验对象都让我离找出
Every subject gets me closer to finding exactly
被k触碰的位置更进一步
where it is He touched us.
但今天不是
Not today, though.
不 今天就先看看哪里会疼
No. Today let's just see where it hurts.
让他住手 乔治
Stop him, George!
就放在他夹克兜里
He's got it in his jacket pocket!
反正我们也不想要
We didn't want it anyway!
该死的婊子
Fucking tart!
那疯子是你朋友吗
Oi. Is that maniac a friend of yours?
阿玛莉亚
Amalia?
特鲁夫人
Mrs. True?
阿代尔
Miss Adair.
-你看起来...  -我...
- You look very... - I've...
刚打了一架
Got into a fight.
已经一天了
It's been a day for that.
我输了
I didn't win.
玛拉黛把小姑娘抢走了
Maladie has the girl.
他们说她叫玛丽・布莱顿
Mary. Brighton, they said.
她不会杀她的
She won't kill her.
不会立马就杀 我们还有时间
Not right away. We have time.
我们... 还有时间
We... have some time.
你找到了很刺激的方法打发时间
And you've found an invigorating way to spend it.
是他们先动手的
They started it.
-不 是我先开始的  -我知道
- No, I started it. - I know.
我明白 麻烦会让你苦恼
I know. Trouble makes you troublesome.
但没什么比好运更能激发你
But nothing sets you off like good fortune.
玛丽的歌
Mary's song.
直击我的内心
Reachin' right into me.
告诉我 我在这里
Tellin' me that that I'm here.
我属于这里
I belong here.
还有你
And you.
而且... 我们都被附魔
And... all of us that's Touched.
我们都被编入世界的网络之中
We're woven into the fabric of the world,
我们注定就是如此
and we're meant to be as we are.
我们会找到玛丽 让她歌唱
We find Mary. We get her singin'.
他们会来到我们身边 就能安全
They'll all come to us, and they'll be safe.
他们并不安全
They won't be safe.
至少不那么孤单
Less lonely, then.
这是个开始
And that's a start.
是个开始
It's a start.
m 34 -191 l 162 -6 l 25 191 l 129 191 l 213 69 l 359 277 l 360 277 l 465 277 l 265 -6 l 394 -191 l 290 -191 l 213 -81 l 137 -191 l 34 -191
m -32 -191 l -32 191 l 14 191 l 54 134 l 54 -146 l 23 -191 l -32 -191
m -353 191 l -354 4 b -352 -98 -345 -191 -175 -191 l -44 -191 l -44 -124 l -179 -124 b -269 -120 -271 -68 -273 -32 l -44 -32 l -44 35 l -273 35 l -273 191 l -353 191
ZIMUXIA.CN
关注新浪微博
@FIX字幕侠